<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Development on MyThinkPond</title>
    <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/tags/software-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Development on MyThinkPond</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 19:23:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://MyThinkPond.com/tags/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Javascript: Embrace Arrow Functions</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-05-03-javascript-embrace-arrow-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 19:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-05-03-javascript-embrace-arrow-functions/</guid>
      <description>Great article on JavaScript currying and arrow functions.&#xA;Here is an example of a function in Javascript:&#xA;const secret = function (msg) { return function () { return msg; }; }; The same function as currying or arrow function:&#xA;const secret = msg =&amp;gt; () =&amp;gt; msg; To learn more about the basics, visit the link below. Source: Familiarity Bias is Holding You Back: It’s Time to Embrace Arrow Functions</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elements of JavaScript Style – JavaScript Scene – Medium</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-05-03-elements-of-javascript-style-javascript-scene-medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 19:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-05-03-elements-of-javascript-style-javascript-scene-medium/</guid>
      <description>Great article focusing on Javascript style. Provides some good examples of JavaScript coding styles, practices, and things to avoid.&#xA;The examples includes:&#xA;Make the function the unit of composition. One job for each function. Omit needless code. Use active voice. Avoid a succession of loose statements. Keep related code together. Put statements and expressions in positive form. Use parallel code for parallel concepts. Source: Elements of JavaScript Style – JavaScript Scene – Medium</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>uvloop - Python replacement for asyncio event loop</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-04-01-uvloop-python-replacement-for-asyncio-event-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 16:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-04-01-uvloop-python-replacement-for-asyncio-event-loop/</guid>
      <description>uvloop is a fast, drop-in replacement of the built-in asyncio event loop. uvloop is implemented in Cython and uses libuv under the hood.&#xA;Benefits: uvloop makes asyncio 2-4x faster.&#xA;Cons: uvloop is available from PyPI but it requires Python 3.5. (The reason for this is asyncio was introduced in Python 3.4 and above.) Unless your project is based on Python 3.4+ - you may not be able to leverage this library.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Web Development: Coding as a Service</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/03/12/the-future-of-web-development-coding-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 18:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/03/12/the-future-of-web-development-coding-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>The article talks about the comoditization of web development as a service (Coding as a Service - CaaS).&#xA;For the price of two Venti Iced Caramel Macchiatos per month you can run a respectable website with little to no technical experience... Artificial Intelligence will enable more complex combinations of code to be fit together through an automated process... The quantity and quality of customization with AI will be staggering. And for the end user this means it will be at once simpler and cheaper.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
