<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspirational on MyThinkPond</title>
    <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/categories/inspirational/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspirational on MyThinkPond</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 10:09:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://MyThinkPond.com/categories/inspirational/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Being Thankful During Thanks Giving and Life&#39;s Possibilities when fueled by Encouragement, Desire, Strength and Determination</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-11-25-lifes-possibilities-with-desire-strength-and-determination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 10:09:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-11-25-lifes-possibilities-with-desire-strength-and-determination/</guid>
      <description>Dear Reader: I read this article on my cousin&amp;rsquo;s Facebook page (links below) and it was originally written in Tamil language. I was inspired when I read it and unfortunately Auto-Translate did not do a great job at translating this story and so this Thanks Giving - I wanted to translate this artcle into Engish so that the Engish-speaking readers can be inspired this Thanks Giving holiday of 2017. With a little bit of Encouragement and with Desire, Stength and Determination - all things are possible!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind Map: A Method To x100 Your Productivity | Robin Sharma</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/09/20/mind-map-a-method-to-x100-your-productivity-robin-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/09/20/mind-map-a-method-to-x100-your-productivity-robin-sharma/</guid>
      <description>Based on this YouTube video: https://youtu.be/cshVfS2LXm0&#xA;By Robin Sharma on &amp;ldquo;A Method To x100 Your Productivity&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Great video on how to improve your productivity by hundred fold. Mind map provided below for the busy folks.&#xA;Cheers!&#xA;Today&#39;s Inspirational Quote &amp;lt;img&#xA;src=&amp;quot;/img/2017/09/avvaiyar.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;avvaiyar&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;50&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;imgframe&amp;quot; &amp;gt; ** Tamil **: கற்றது கைமண் அளவு, கட்காதது உலகளவு.&#xA;** English Pronounciation **: Katrathu Kaiman Alavu Kallathathu Ulagalavu&#xA;** English Translation **: Known is a drop, unknown is an ocean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Companies Give Back Moment (repost) </title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/09/05/tech-companies-give-back-moment-repost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/09/05/tech-companies-give-back-moment-repost/</guid>
      <description>We now exist an interesting interstitial moment, one defined by big corporations producing much of the innovation and some of the world’s richest companies – Apple, Amazon, Uber, Facebook – trying to solve big hairy problems. These are the problems that startups would have once solved but because they are so expensive – I’m talking about commercial VR, self-driving trucks, gene editing, and the like – there are no startups capitalized to tackle them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three shadows during the eclipse. Science behind it. </title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/08/19/three-shadows-during-the-eclipse-science-behind-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 17:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/08/19/three-shadows-during-the-eclipse-science-behind-it/</guid>
      <description>On their journey through space, the Earth and the Moon cast 3 different shadows causing different types of solar and lunar eclipses. Why are there 3 shadows? https://www.timeanddate.com/eclipse/shadows.html</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New &#39;responsive&#39; Google Font can shapeshift to match any design</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/07/04/new-responsive-google-font-can-shapeshift-to-match-any-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/07/04/new-responsive-google-font-can-shapeshift-to-match-any-design/</guid>
      <description>Google has added its very first &amp;lsquo;parametric&amp;rsquo; font that boasts a responsive design which you can easily tweak without almost any limitations.&#xA;Source: New &amp;lsquo;responsive&amp;rsquo; Google Font can shapeshift to match any design</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanofridge could keep quantum computers cool enough to calculate</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/nanofridge-could-keep-quantum-computers-cool-enough-to-calculate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/nanofridge-could-keep-quantum-computers-cool-enough-to-calculate/</guid>
      <description>Quantum computers need to be kept cool, just like regular computers, but an ordinary fan won’t cut it. A nanofridge that sorts electrons by temperature just might keep it cool enough to allow quantum compute.&#xA;Classical computers require built-in fans and other ways to dissipate heat, and quantum computers are no different. Instead of working with bits of information that can be either 0 or 1, as in a classical machine, a quantum computer relies on “qubits”, which can be in both states simultaneously – called a superposition – thanks to the quirks of quantum mechanics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT physicists have found a brand new way to unleash graphene&#39;s superconductive power</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/mit-physicists-have-found-a-brand-new-way-to-unleash-graphenes-superconductive-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/mit-physicists-have-found-a-brand-new-way-to-unleash-graphenes-superconductive-power/</guid>
      <description>Physicists have found a new way to turn &#39;wonder material&#39; graphene into a ridiculously powerful superconductor, capable of shuttling electricity with zero resistance. That&amp;rsquo;s important, because if we could find a way to achieve superconductivity at room temperature, it would lead to vastly more efficient electronic devices, not to mention power lines. Right now, energy companies are losing about 7 percent of their energy as heat as a result of resistance in the grid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists Found Cancer-Causing DNA in Stem Cells Given to Patients - Tonic</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/28/scientists-found-cancer-causing-dna-in-stem-cells-given-to-patients-tonic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 21:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/28/scientists-found-cancer-causing-dna-in-stem-cells-given-to-patients-tonic/</guid>
      <description>https://tonic.vice.com/en_us/article/scientists-found-cancer-causing-dna-in-stem-cells-given-to-patients</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if we’re living in a computer simulation? | Technology | The Guardian</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/24/what-if-were-living-in-a-computer-simulation-technology-the-guardian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 15:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/24/what-if-were-living-in-a-computer-simulation-technology-the-guardian/</guid>
      <description>Virtual reality technology is making great advances, but it has also helped popularise a theory long debated by philosophers and now gaining supporters in Silicon Valley – that the outside world is itself a simulation&#xA;Source: What if we’re living in a computer simulation? | Technology | The Guardian</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Researchers Unearthed a New Copy of the Declaration of Independence</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/22/researchers-unearthed-a-new-copy-of-the-declaration-of-independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 22:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/22/researchers-unearthed-a-new-copy-of-the-declaration-of-independence/</guid>
      <description>http://www.esquire.com/news-politics/news/a54689/new-declaration-of-independence/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article: Physicists observe &#39;negative mass&#39;</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-physicists-observe-negative-mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 16:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-physicists-observe-negative-mass/</guid>
      <description>Physicists observe &amp;rsquo;negative mass&#39;&#xA;http://flip.it/zOX5Z5</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article: Why Does The Proton Spin? Physics Holds A Surprising Answer</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-why-does-the-proton-spin-physics-holds-a-surprising-answer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 16:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-why-does-the-proton-spin-physics-holds-a-surprising-answer/</guid>
      <description>Why Does The Proton Spin? Physics Holds A Surprising Answer&#xA;http://flip.it/ZBiAfu</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Teenager Just &#34;Delighted&#34; NASA By Pointing Out a Significant Error in Their Data</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/03/24/a-teenager-just-delighted-nasa-by-pointing-out-a-significant-error-in-their-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 02:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/03/24/a-teenager-just-delighted-nasa-by-pointing-out-a-significant-error-in-their-data/</guid>
      <description>https://futurism.com/a-teenager-just-delighted-nasa-by-pointing-out-a-significant-error-in-their-data/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Isro launches 104 satellites in a single mission to create world record</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/02/19/isro-launches-104-satellites-in-a-single-mission-to-create-world-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 02:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/02/19/isro-launches-104-satellites-in-a-single-mission-to-create-world-record/</guid>
      <description>India&amp;rsquo;s Isro’s [] PSLV-C37 in a single payload, included the Cartosat-2 series and 103 co-passenger satellites, together weighing over 650kg&#xA;Great achievement especially considering only three of the 103 satellites belonged to India making this mission one of the most business sense launch of this century! Kudos to India!&#xA;Read more about it at the link below.&#xA;Source: Isro launches 104 satellites in a single mission to create world record - Livemint</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials science: How to keep cool without costing the Earth</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/02/16/materials-science-how-to-keep-cool-without-costing-the-earth-the-economist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 18:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/02/16/materials-science-how-to-keep-cool-without-costing-the-earth-the-economist/</guid>
      <description>The new film works by a process called radiative cooling. This takes advantage of that fact that Earth’s atmosphere allows certain wavelengths of heat-carrying infrared radiation to escape into space unimpeded. Convert unwanted heat into infrared of the correct wavelength, then, and you can dump it into the cosmos with no come back. &amp;hellip;their film, placed atop an average American house, would be enough to keep the internal temperature at 20°C on a day when it was 37°C outside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year 2017</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/01/01/happy-new-year-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 15:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/01/01/happy-new-year-2017/</guid>
      <description>தங்களுக்கும், தங்கள் குடும்பததினொறுக்கும் எங்கள் புத்தாண்டு நள்வாழ்த்துக்கள். (Tamil)&#xA;Wishing you and your family a happy new year 2017.&#xA;Cheers!&#xA;_Today&#39;s inspirational quote:_ [![bust_of_marcusaurelius](/img/2016/11/bust_of_marcusaurelius.jpg)](/img/2016/11/bust_of_marcusaurelius.jpg) Take inventory of this past year. Realize what is up to us and what is not up to us.&#xA;We can control our emotions, our decisions, our perspectives, and our desires. We have a say in how these things go. These are things that are up to us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repost: Mapping the End of Malaria</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/11/05/republish-mapping-the-end-of-malaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 14:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/11/05/republish-mapping-the-end-of-malaria/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the End of Malaria by Bill Gates&#xA;The article discusses two important points:&#xA;How Malaria is putting mosquitoes as the #1 deadliest lifeform that kills humans? (Interestingly humans are the #2 lifeform that kills our own species) And what has/is being done to change this through the Gates Foundation in the developing countries. As well as the positive, measurable changes that can be seen from the last decade.&#xA;Addresses a underlying issue on foreign aid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmer Levels - humor</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/16/programmer-levels-humor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 18:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/16/programmer-levels-humor/</guid>
      <description>Credit: http://turnoff.us/image/en/programmer-levels.png</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photos from the Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/14/photos-from-the-basilica-of-the-national-shrine-of-the-immaculate-conception/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 20:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/14/photos-from-the-basilica-of-the-national-shrine-of-the-immaculate-conception/</guid>
      <description>Recently visited the Basilica of the National Shrine and each time I visit this beautiful place I&amp;rsquo;m spellbound. It is one of the hidden gems to visit when you are visiting the capital. Here are some pictures from my recent visit.&#xA;Click here for the photos from the Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception in Michigan Avenue, Washington, DC. The beautiful murals are a work of art!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s weekend!</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/14/its-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 19:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/14/its-weekend/</guid>
      <description>To learn more about where the joke came from, click this link. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget Software—Now Hackers Are Exploiting Physics | WIRED</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/09/03/forget-software-now-hackers-are-exploiting-physics-wired/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 21:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/09/03/forget-software-now-hackers-are-exploiting-physics-wired/</guid>
      <description>[Forget Software—Now Hackers Are Exploiting Physics | WIRED] is good,have a look at it!&#xA;targeting the actual electricity that comprises bits of data in computer memory. Technique is called &#39;RowHammer&#39;. The trick works by running a program on the target computer, which repeatedly overwrites a certain row of transistors in its DRAM flash memory, “hammering” it until a rare glitch occurs: Electric charge leaks from the hammered row of transistors into an adjacent row.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egyptian History as we know today</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/24/egyptian-history-as-we-know-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 16:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/24/egyptian-history-as-we-know-today/</guid>
      <description>Much of the Egyptian/Nubian history and culture we know today was a result of colonization by the European empires. In their thirst for expansion, they colonized much of the known world.&#xA;In India, the Dutch, the Portuguese then the British all came under the name of colonization and expansion. They came in search of new trade-routes to the orient and as history has it, the interests of trade slowly turned into colonization and expansion of the empire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My daughter found a four-leaf clover the day before Saint Patrick&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/16/my-daughter-found-a-four-leaf-clover-the-day-before-saint-patricks-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 23:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/16/my-daughter-found-a-four-leaf-clover-the-day-before-saint-patricks-day/</guid>
      <description>My daughter found a four-leaf clover the day before Saint Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day! Talk about luck!&#xA;four-leaf clover&#xA;According to the Wikipedia article:&#xA;It has been estimated that there are approximately 10,000 three-leaf clovers for every one four-leaf clover She should have played the lottery!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Age Of Light: Two BIG innovations in Graphene and nano technology can forge a new future for mankind</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/08/27/welcome-to-the-age-of-light-two-big-innovations-in-graphene-and-nano-technology-can-forge-a-new-future-for-mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 17:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/08/27/welcome-to-the-age-of-light-two-big-innovations-in-graphene-and-nano-technology-can-forge-a-new-future-for-mankind/</guid>
      <description>#AgeOfLight&#xA;As I was reading today&amp;rsquo;s news (Science) breakthroughs, I came across two independent discovery/invention but combined makes a HUGE breakthrough and paves the way for a BIGHTER FUTURE!!!&#xA;If this peeks your interest read further.&#xA;[#1] Invention: Manufacturing Graphene using Tea-Extract&#xA;What problem does this solve? Today, manufacturing Graphene takes a lot of time and can only produce/grow small amounts of the material. It takes a lot of energy, raw-material and time - to produce the small quantities of the product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words of Wisdom - Our paradox of our time in history</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2010/07/08/words-of-wisdom-our-paradox-of-our-time-in-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 15:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2010/07/08/words-of-wisdom-our-paradox-of-our-time-in-history/</guid>
      <description>The paradox of our time in history is that we have taller buildings but shorter tempers, wider Freeways , but narrower viewpoints. We spend more, but have less, we buy more, but enjoy less. We have bigger houses and smaller families, more conveniences, but less time. We have more degrees but less sense, more knowledge, but less judgment, more experts, yet more problems, more medicine, but less wellness.&#xA;We drink too much, smoke too much, spend too recklessly, laugh too little, drive too fast, get too angry, stay up too late, get up too tired, read too little, watch TV too much, and pray too seldom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humor of the day on Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2010/02/24/humor-of-the-day-on-fourier-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 22:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2010/02/24/humor-of-the-day-on-fourier-transform/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s an IEEE joke. This one got me laughing for quite some time. http://xkcd.com/26/ http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/fourier.jpg&#xA;Cheers</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
