<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science and Technology on MyThinkPond</title>
    <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/categories/science-and-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science and Technology on MyThinkPond</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:47:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://MyThinkPond.com/categories/science-and-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tech Companies Give Back Moment (repost) </title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/09/05/tech-companies-give-back-moment-repost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/09/05/tech-companies-give-back-moment-repost/</guid>
      <description>We now exist an interesting interstitial moment, one defined by big corporations producing much of the innovation and some of the world’s richest companies – Apple, Amazon, Uber, Facebook – trying to solve big hairy problems. These are the problems that startups would have once solved but because they are so expensive – I’m talking about commercial VR, self-driving trucks, gene editing, and the like – there are no startups capitalized to tackle them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three shadows during the eclipse. Science behind it. </title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/08/19/three-shadows-during-the-eclipse-science-behind-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 17:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/08/19/three-shadows-during-the-eclipse-science-behind-it/</guid>
      <description>On their journey through space, the Earth and the Moon cast 3 different shadows causing different types of solar and lunar eclipses. Why are there 3 shadows? https://www.timeanddate.com/eclipse/shadows.html</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New &#39;responsive&#39; Google Font can shapeshift to match any design</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/07/04/new-responsive-google-font-can-shapeshift-to-match-any-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/07/04/new-responsive-google-font-can-shapeshift-to-match-any-design/</guid>
      <description>Google has added its very first &amp;lsquo;parametric&amp;rsquo; font that boasts a responsive design which you can easily tweak without almost any limitations.&#xA;Source: New &amp;lsquo;responsive&amp;rsquo; Google Font can shapeshift to match any design</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ancient, giant viruses are being unearthed in Arctic ice that&#39;s at risk of melting</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/ancient-giant-viruses-are-being-unearthed-in-arctic-ice-thats-at-risk-of-melting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/ancient-giant-viruses-are-being-unearthed-in-arctic-ice-thats-at-risk-of-melting/</guid>
      <description>Scientists working in the Arctic circle over the past few decades have unearthed several massive viruses that some say could be re-awakened if the permafrost that imprisons them dissolves. Recently, some researchers have suggested that these enormous viruses could thaw out, escape, and make lots of people sick. It sounds like something out of a 1990s horror film. But you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t get too concerned — at least not yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Need to Know About Nuclear Physics</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/everything-you-need-to-know-about-nuclear-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/everything-you-need-to-know-about-nuclear-physics/</guid>
      <description>[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lUhJL7o6_cA[/embed]&#xA;Shini from the YouTube series CrashCourse takes a dive into the world of Einstein and nuclear physics.&#xA;Source: Everything You Need to Know About Nuclear Physics</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing Demands a Whole New Kind of Programmer</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/quantum-computing-demands-a-whole-new-kind-of-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/quantum-computing-demands-a-whole-new-kind-of-programmer/</guid>
      <description>[![](/img/2017/05/quantum-computing-whole-new-kind-of-programmer-1-1068x601.jpg)](https://singularityhub.com/2017/05/09/quantum-computing-demands-a-whole-new-kind-of-programmer/)Quantum computers finally seem to be coming of age with promises of “quantum supremacy” by the end of the year. But there’s a problem—very few people know how to work them. The bold claim of achieving &#34;quantum supremacy&#34; came on the back of Google unveiling a new quantum chip design. The hyperbolic phrase essentially means building a quantum device that can perform a calculation impossible for any conventional computer. The technology has a major challenge to overcome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanofridge could keep quantum computers cool enough to calculate</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/nanofridge-could-keep-quantum-computers-cool-enough-to-calculate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/nanofridge-could-keep-quantum-computers-cool-enough-to-calculate/</guid>
      <description>Quantum computers need to be kept cool, just like regular computers, but an ordinary fan won’t cut it. A nanofridge that sorts electrons by temperature just might keep it cool enough to allow quantum compute.&#xA;Classical computers require built-in fans and other ways to dissipate heat, and quantum computers are no different. Instead of working with bits of information that can be either 0 or 1, as in a classical machine, a quantum computer relies on “qubits”, which can be in both states simultaneously – called a superposition – thanks to the quirks of quantum mechanics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT physicists have found a brand new way to unleash graphene&#39;s superconductive power</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/mit-physicists-have-found-a-brand-new-way-to-unleash-graphenes-superconductive-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/mit-physicists-have-found-a-brand-new-way-to-unleash-graphenes-superconductive-power/</guid>
      <description>Physicists have found a new way to turn &#39;wonder material&#39; graphene into a ridiculously powerful superconductor, capable of shuttling electricity with zero resistance. That&amp;rsquo;s important, because if we could find a way to achieve superconductivity at room temperature, it would lead to vastly more efficient electronic devices, not to mention power lines. Right now, energy companies are losing about 7 percent of their energy as heat as a result of resistance in the grid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stunning image of Jupiter from NASA&#39;s Juno spacecraft is simply out of this world — except it&#39;s not</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/stunning-image-of-jupiter-from-nasas-juno-spacecraft-is-simply-out-of-this-world-except-its-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/stunning-image-of-jupiter-from-nasas-juno-spacecraft-is-simply-out-of-this-world-except-its-not/</guid>
      <description>The filagree of atmospheric patterns at Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s south pole bears an eerie resemblance to a phenomenon here on Earth&#xA;Source: This stunning image of Jupiter from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Juno spacecraft is simply out of this world — except it&amp;rsquo;s not</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting to Grips With Time Crystals. What is That Really?</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/getting-to-grips-with-time-crystals-what-is-that-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/getting-to-grips-with-time-crystals-what-is-that-really/</guid>
      <description>You may or may not have heard that there’s a new phase of matter been discovered and it’s called a time crystal. A team of UC Berkley physicists made the discovery last year and since t…&#xA;Source: Getting to Grips With Time Crystals. What is That Really? | TrendinTech</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if we’re living in a computer simulation? | Technology | The Guardian</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/24/what-if-were-living-in-a-computer-simulation-technology-the-guardian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 15:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/24/what-if-were-living-in-a-computer-simulation-technology-the-guardian/</guid>
      <description>Virtual reality technology is making great advances, but it has also helped popularise a theory long debated by philosophers and now gaining supporters in Silicon Valley – that the outside world is itself a simulation&#xA;Source: What if we’re living in a computer simulation? | Technology | The Guardian</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article: Physicists observe &#39;negative mass&#39;</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-physicists-observe-negative-mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 16:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-physicists-observe-negative-mass/</guid>
      <description>Physicists observe &amp;rsquo;negative mass&#39;&#xA;http://flip.it/zOX5Z5</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article: Why Does The Proton Spin? Physics Holds A Surprising Answer</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-why-does-the-proton-spin-physics-holds-a-surprising-answer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 16:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-why-does-the-proton-spin-physics-holds-a-surprising-answer/</guid>
      <description>Why Does The Proton Spin? Physics Holds A Surprising Answer&#xA;http://flip.it/ZBiAfu</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Teenager Just &#34;Delighted&#34; NASA By Pointing Out a Significant Error in Their Data</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/03/24/a-teenager-just-delighted-nasa-by-pointing-out-a-significant-error-in-their-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 02:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/03/24/a-teenager-just-delighted-nasa-by-pointing-out-a-significant-error-in-their-data/</guid>
      <description>https://futurism.com/a-teenager-just-delighted-nasa-by-pointing-out-a-significant-error-in-their-data/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Web Development: Coding as a Service</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/03/12/the-future-of-web-development-coding-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 18:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/03/12/the-future-of-web-development-coding-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>The article talks about the comoditization of web development as a service (Coding as a Service - CaaS).&#xA;For the price of two Venti Iced Caramel Macchiatos per month you can run a respectable website with little to no technical experience... Artificial Intelligence will enable more complex combinations of code to be fit together through an automated process... The quantity and quality of customization with AI will be staggering. And for the end user this means it will be at once simpler and cheaper.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Isro launches 104 satellites in a single mission to create world record</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/02/19/isro-launches-104-satellites-in-a-single-mission-to-create-world-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 02:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/02/19/isro-launches-104-satellites-in-a-single-mission-to-create-world-record/</guid>
      <description>India&amp;rsquo;s Isro’s [] PSLV-C37 in a single payload, included the Cartosat-2 series and 103 co-passenger satellites, together weighing over 650kg&#xA;Great achievement especially considering only three of the 103 satellites belonged to India making this mission one of the most business sense launch of this century! Kudos to India!&#xA;Read more about it at the link below.&#xA;Source: Isro launches 104 satellites in a single mission to create world record - Livemint</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the Real Schrodinger’s Cat Please Stand Up | Hackaday</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/20/will-the-real-schrodingers-cat-please-stand-up-hackaday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 02:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/20/will-the-real-schrodingers-cat-please-stand-up-hackaday/</guid>
      <description>Interesting read on Schrodinger’s Cat and papers from Einstein.&#xA;The story of Schrodinger’s cat is well known, and one of quantum theory’s most popular phrases on the world stage. You can find his cat on t-shirts, bumper stickers, internet memes and the like. However, few know the origins of the cat, and how it came into being. In this article we’re going to explore not so much the cat, but the meaning behind the thought experiment and what it is meant to convey, while keeping it simple enough for anyone to understand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget Software—Now Hackers Are Exploiting Physics | WIRED</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/09/03/forget-software-now-hackers-are-exploiting-physics-wired/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 21:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/09/03/forget-software-now-hackers-are-exploiting-physics-wired/</guid>
      <description>[Forget Software—Now Hackers Are Exploiting Physics | WIRED] is good,have a look at it!&#xA;targeting the actual electricity that comprises bits of data in computer memory. Technique is called &#39;RowHammer&#39;. The trick works by running a program on the target computer, which repeatedly overwrites a certain row of transistors in its DRAM flash memory, “hammering” it until a rare glitch occurs: Electric charge leaks from the hammered row of transistors into an adjacent row.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bizarre fourth state of water discovered</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/18/bizarre-fourth-state-of-water-discovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 17:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/18/bizarre-fourth-state-of-water-discovered/</guid>
      <description>Bizarre fourth state of water discovered Scientists at the Oak Ridge National Lab (ORNL) have discovered that when (water) put under extreme pressure in small spaces, the life-giving liquid can exhibit a strange fourth state known as &#34;tunneling&#34;. Quantum tunneling means that a particle, or in this case a molecule, can overcome a barrier and be on both sides of it at once – or anywhere in between. Think of rolling a ball down one side of a hill and up another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article: The spherical genius of the Hüttlin Kugelmotor</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/18/article-the-spherical-genius-of-the-huttlin-kugelmotor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 17:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/18/article-the-spherical-genius-of-the-huttlin-kugelmotor/</guid>
      <description>The spherical genius of the Hüttlin Kugelmotor Electrical motors are an energy-efficient method for driving vehicles but battery technology is simply not going to advance quickly enough for all-electric vehicles to be a practical reality for most uses anytime soon. The near and mid-term future is undoubtedly a combination of compact combustion engine generators charging dense battery packs that drive electric motors - the &#34;range extender&#34; option. After nearly twenty years of development another &amp;ldquo;range extender&amp;rdquo; candidate is going through final testing and it is a work of elegant genius - Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appeals Court Hands Obama Administration Major Win In Net Neutrality Case</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/14/appeals-court-hands-obama-administration-major-win-in-net-neutrality-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 15:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/14/appeals-court-hands-obama-administration-major-win-in-net-neutrality-case/</guid>
      <description>Appeals Court Hands Obama Administration Major Win In Net Neutrality Case&#xA;The Obama administration’s rules prevent internet service providers from charging content producers for faster or more reliable service, a practice known as “paid prioritization.” The rules also ban blocking and purposefully slowing the traffic of lawful services, and apply to both mobile and fixed broadband service. Today’s ruling is a victory for consumers and innovators who deserve unfettered access to the entire web, and it ensures the internet remains a platform for unparalleled innovation, free expression and economic growth</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New &#39;Superman&#39; crystals can store data for billions of years</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/13/new-superman-crystals-can-store-data-for-billions-of-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 14:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/13/new-superman-crystals-can-store-data-for-billions-of-years/</guid>
      <description>New &amp;lsquo;Superman&amp;rsquo; crystals can store data for billions of years&#xA;http://money.cnn.com/2016/02/17/technology/5d-data-storage-memory-crystals/index.html?iid=surge-story-summary</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intel&#39;s miracle chip could make your gadgets 1,000 times faster</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/13/intels-miracle-chip-could-make-your-gadgets-1000-times-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 14:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/13/intels-miracle-chip-could-make-your-gadgets-1000-times-faster/</guid>
      <description>Intel and Micron say they have a new computer chip that will make your gadgets significantly faster, more durable and able to store way more data.&#xA;http://money.cnn.com/2015/07/29/technology/intel-3d-xpoint-chip/index.html?iid=EL</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists believe they have found a way to make a universal cancer vaccine</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/01/scientists-believe-they-have-found-a-way-to-make-a-universal-cancer-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 18:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/01/scientists-believe-they-have-found-a-way-to-make-a-universal-cancer-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/science/cancer-vaccine-immunotherapy-universal-immune-system-rna-nature-journal-a7060181.html</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
