<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>time on MyThinkPond</title>
    <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/tags/time/</link>
    <description>Recent content in time on MyThinkPond</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://MyThinkPond.com/tags/time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Managing your time - Time-Block Method with free Templates (revised)</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2022-01-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2022-01-1/</guid>
      <description>Updates:&#xA;Compiled a series of q&amp;amp;a asked by blog readers over the year in hopes that my answers help others. The questions and answers are at the bottom of this article. What is this article about? There is an Eastern philosophy that summarizes the importance of time management. And it goes something link this:&#xA;How we spend our day is how we spend our lives. and another philosophy that summarizes the value of time</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to sync your date when you restore a VirtualBox snapshot?</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/11/05/how-to-sync-your-date-when-you-restore-a-virtualbox-snapshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 16:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/11/05/how-to-sync-your-date-when-you-restore-a-virtualbox-snapshot/</guid>
      <description>This article focuses on synchronizing/updating the clock in your guest linux VM after you restore a VirtualBox snapshot.&#xA;When you create a VirtualBox snapshot, it&amp;rsquo;s essentially a photo taken and frozen in time. All bits including the date and time are frozen to that instant. When you restore a snapshot, the Linux guest VM system is restored back to that snapshot including the date and time. This may not be desired all the time especially if the purpose is to restore the configuration and settings to an earlier time but your want to roll forward the clock on the VM to the present instance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
