<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spring Boot on MyThinkPond</title>
    <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/tags/spring-boot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spring Boot on MyThinkPond</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 23:53:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://MyThinkPond.com/tags/spring-boot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Microservices</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2019-09-06-understanding_microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 23:53:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2019-09-06-understanding_microservices/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Understanding how we got here and the problem that it solves will help understand what Microservices is all about.&#xA;A few months back, I gave a presentation at Leidos Cloud User Group on the topic of &amp;ldquo;Understanding Microservices&amp;rdquo;. To my astonishment, we had about 123 folks that attended the presentation. I felt that it&amp;rsquo;s best that I share this knowledge with the world. I have also created a short (and sweet) implementation of Microservices using JavaScript Cote.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring Framework - Application Context - three ways to get to the application context</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-11-24-spring-framework-three-ways-to-application-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 13:28:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-11-24-spring-framework-three-ways-to-application-context/</guid>
      <description>This article shows you three different ways how to get to the Spring Framework Application Context in your code.&#xA;Summary (This is a repost of an older article I wrote in 2010). In searching Google for &amp;ldquo;Spring ApplicationContextAware&amp;rdquo;, you will come across a lot of recommendations and I also see a lot of folks continuing to complain saying that their setApplicationContext method does not get invoked. So to help clarify, I&amp;rsquo;m blogging a few notes in hope that it helps clarify how the context works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring Framework - Application Context - three ways to get to the application context</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2010-03-22-spring-application-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 17:09:21 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2010-03-22-spring-application-context/</guid>
      <description>Summary This article shows you three different ways how to get to the Spring Framework Application Context in your code. test</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
