<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on MyThinkPond</title>
    <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on MyThinkPond</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 18:11:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://MyThinkPond.com/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dear Readers, Happy New Year - 2018</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2018-01-01-happy-new-year-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 18:11:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2018-01-01-happy-new-year-2018/</guid>
      <description>For all of my wonderful blog readers out there, I want to say &amp;ldquo;THANK YOU&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Wishing You All A Happy New Year!&#xA;May your 2018 be the best year ever!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converted Wordpress.com Hosted Blog to Hugo Static Blog :-)</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-09-23-converting-wordpress-hosted-blog-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 23:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/post/2017-09-23-converting-wordpress-hosted-blog-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Summary Thanks to Hugo Static Site generator written in GoLang and Mainroad Theme, I was able to port over my personal blog MyThinkPond as a static generated website.&#xA;Before and After Here is a screenshot of the belore site:&#xA;MyThinkPond under Wordpress hosting&#xA;Here is a screenshot of the belore site:&#xA;MyThinkPond under Wordpress hosting&#xA;I think it&amp;rsquo;s a move in the right direction. Putting me in complete control of the content, images and all artifacts that goes into bundling the site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind Map: A Method To x100 Your Productivity | Robin Sharma</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/09/20/mind-map-a-method-to-x100-your-productivity-robin-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 22:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/09/20/mind-map-a-method-to-x100-your-productivity-robin-sharma/</guid>
      <description>Based on this YouTube video: https://youtu.be/cshVfS2LXm0&#xA;By Robin Sharma on &amp;ldquo;A Method To x100 Your Productivity&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Great video on how to improve your productivity by hundred fold. Mind map provided below for the busy folks.&#xA;Cheers!&#xA;Today&#39;s Inspirational Quote &amp;lt;img&#xA;src=&amp;quot;/img/2017/09/avvaiyar.jpg&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;avvaiyar&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;50&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;imgframe&amp;quot; &amp;gt; ** Tamil **: கற்றது கைமண் அளவு, கட்காதது உலகளவு.&#xA;** English Pronounciation **: Katrathu Kaiman Alavu Kallathathu Ulagalavu&#xA;** English Translation **: Known is a drop, unknown is an ocean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three shadows during the eclipse. Science behind it. </title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/08/19/three-shadows-during-the-eclipse-science-behind-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 17:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/08/19/three-shadows-during-the-eclipse-science-behind-it/</guid>
      <description>On their journey through space, the Earth and the Moon cast 3 different shadows causing different types of solar and lunar eclipses. Why are there 3 shadows? https://www.timeanddate.com/eclipse/shadows.html</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ancient, giant viruses are being unearthed in Arctic ice that&#39;s at risk of melting</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/ancient-giant-viruses-are-being-unearthed-in-arctic-ice-thats-at-risk-of-melting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/ancient-giant-viruses-are-being-unearthed-in-arctic-ice-thats-at-risk-of-melting/</guid>
      <description>Scientists working in the Arctic circle over the past few decades have unearthed several massive viruses that some say could be re-awakened if the permafrost that imprisons them dissolves. Recently, some researchers have suggested that these enormous viruses could thaw out, escape, and make lots of people sick. It sounds like something out of a 1990s horror film. But you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t get too concerned — at least not yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Need to Know About Nuclear Physics</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/everything-you-need-to-know-about-nuclear-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/everything-you-need-to-know-about-nuclear-physics/</guid>
      <description>[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lUhJL7o6_cA[/embed]&#xA;Shini from the YouTube series CrashCourse takes a dive into the world of Einstein and nuclear physics.&#xA;Source: Everything You Need to Know About Nuclear Physics</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Computing Demands a Whole New Kind of Programmer</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/quantum-computing-demands-a-whole-new-kind-of-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/quantum-computing-demands-a-whole-new-kind-of-programmer/</guid>
      <description>[![](/img/2017/05/quantum-computing-whole-new-kind-of-programmer-1-1068x601.jpg)](https://singularityhub.com/2017/05/09/quantum-computing-demands-a-whole-new-kind-of-programmer/)Quantum computers finally seem to be coming of age with promises of “quantum supremacy” by the end of the year. But there’s a problem—very few people know how to work them. The bold claim of achieving &#34;quantum supremacy&#34; came on the back of Google unveiling a new quantum chip design. The hyperbolic phrase essentially means building a quantum device that can perform a calculation impossible for any conventional computer. The technology has a major challenge to overcome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanofridge could keep quantum computers cool enough to calculate</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/nanofridge-could-keep-quantum-computers-cool-enough-to-calculate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/nanofridge-could-keep-quantum-computers-cool-enough-to-calculate/</guid>
      <description>Quantum computers need to be kept cool, just like regular computers, but an ordinary fan won’t cut it. A nanofridge that sorts electrons by temperature just might keep it cool enough to allow quantum compute.&#xA;Classical computers require built-in fans and other ways to dissipate heat, and quantum computers are no different. Instead of working with bits of information that can be either 0 or 1, as in a classical machine, a quantum computer relies on “qubits”, which can be in both states simultaneously – called a superposition – thanks to the quirks of quantum mechanics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT physicists have found a brand new way to unleash graphene&#39;s superconductive power</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/mit-physicists-have-found-a-brand-new-way-to-unleash-graphenes-superconductive-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/mit-physicists-have-found-a-brand-new-way-to-unleash-graphenes-superconductive-power/</guid>
      <description>Physicists have found a new way to turn &#39;wonder material&#39; graphene into a ridiculously powerful superconductor, capable of shuttling electricity with zero resistance. That&amp;rsquo;s important, because if we could find a way to achieve superconductivity at room temperature, it would lead to vastly more efficient electronic devices, not to mention power lines. Right now, energy companies are losing about 7 percent of their energy as heat as a result of resistance in the grid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stunning image of Jupiter from NASA&#39;s Juno spacecraft is simply out of this world — except it&#39;s not</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/stunning-image-of-jupiter-from-nasas-juno-spacecraft-is-simply-out-of-this-world-except-its-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 01:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/05/11/stunning-image-of-jupiter-from-nasas-juno-spacecraft-is-simply-out-of-this-world-except-its-not/</guid>
      <description>The filagree of atmospheric patterns at Jupiter&amp;rsquo;s south pole bears an eerie resemblance to a phenomenon here on Earth&#xA;Source: This stunning image of Jupiter from NASA&amp;rsquo;s Juno spacecraft is simply out of this world — except it&amp;rsquo;s not</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists Found Cancer-Causing DNA in Stem Cells Given to Patients - Tonic</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/28/scientists-found-cancer-causing-dna-in-stem-cells-given-to-patients-tonic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 21:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/28/scientists-found-cancer-causing-dna-in-stem-cells-given-to-patients-tonic/</guid>
      <description>https://tonic.vice.com/en_us/article/scientists-found-cancer-causing-dna-in-stem-cells-given-to-patients</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if we’re living in a computer simulation? | Technology | The Guardian</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/24/what-if-were-living-in-a-computer-simulation-technology-the-guardian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 15:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/24/what-if-were-living-in-a-computer-simulation-technology-the-guardian/</guid>
      <description>Virtual reality technology is making great advances, but it has also helped popularise a theory long debated by philosophers and now gaining supporters in Silicon Valley – that the outside world is itself a simulation&#xA;Source: What if we’re living in a computer simulation? | Technology | The Guardian</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article: Physicists observe &#39;negative mass&#39;</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-physicists-observe-negative-mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 16:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-physicists-observe-negative-mass/</guid>
      <description>Physicists observe &amp;rsquo;negative mass&#39;&#xA;http://flip.it/zOX5Z5</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article: Why Does The Proton Spin? Physics Holds A Surprising Answer</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-why-does-the-proton-spin-physics-holds-a-surprising-answer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 16:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/04/20/article-why-does-the-proton-spin-physics-holds-a-surprising-answer/</guid>
      <description>Why Does The Proton Spin? Physics Holds A Surprising Answer&#xA;http://flip.it/ZBiAfu</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year 2017</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/01/01/happy-new-year-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 15:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2017/01/01/happy-new-year-2017/</guid>
      <description>தங்களுக்கும், தங்கள் குடும்பததினொறுக்கும் எங்கள் புத்தாண்டு நள்வாழ்த்துக்கள். (Tamil)&#xA;Wishing you and your family a happy new year 2017.&#xA;Cheers!&#xA;_Today&#39;s inspirational quote:_ [![bust_of_marcusaurelius](/img/2016/11/bust_of_marcusaurelius.jpg)](/img/2016/11/bust_of_marcusaurelius.jpg) Take inventory of this past year. Realize what is up to us and what is not up to us.&#xA;We can control our emotions, our decisions, our perspectives, and our desires. We have a say in how these things go. These are things that are up to us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repost: Mapping the End of Malaria</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/11/05/republish-mapping-the-end-of-malaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 14:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/11/05/republish-mapping-the-end-of-malaria/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the End of Malaria by Bill Gates&#xA;The article discusses two important points:&#xA;How Malaria is putting mosquitoes as the #1 deadliest lifeform that kills humans? (Interestingly humans are the #2 lifeform that kills our own species) And what has/is being done to change this through the Gates Foundation in the developing countries. As well as the positive, measurable changes that can be seen from the last decade.&#xA;Addresses a underlying issue on foreign aid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the Real Schrodinger’s Cat Please Stand Up | Hackaday</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/20/will-the-real-schrodingers-cat-please-stand-up-hackaday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 02:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/20/will-the-real-schrodingers-cat-please-stand-up-hackaday/</guid>
      <description>Interesting read on Schrodinger’s Cat and papers from Einstein.&#xA;The story of Schrodinger’s cat is well known, and one of quantum theory’s most popular phrases on the world stage. You can find his cat on t-shirts, bumper stickers, internet memes and the like. However, few know the origins of the cat, and how it came into being. In this article we’re going to explore not so much the cat, but the meaning behind the thought experiment and what it is meant to convey, while keeping it simple enough for anyone to understand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmer Levels - humor</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/16/programmer-levels-humor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 18:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/16/programmer-levels-humor/</guid>
      <description>Credit: http://turnoff.us/image/en/programmer-levels.png</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photos from the Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/14/photos-from-the-basilica-of-the-national-shrine-of-the-immaculate-conception/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 20:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/14/photos-from-the-basilica-of-the-national-shrine-of-the-immaculate-conception/</guid>
      <description>Recently visited the Basilica of the National Shrine and each time I visit this beautiful place I&amp;rsquo;m spellbound. It is one of the hidden gems to visit when you are visiting the capital. Here are some pictures from my recent visit.&#xA;Click here for the photos from the Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception in Michigan Avenue, Washington, DC. The beautiful murals are a work of art!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s weekend!</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/14/its-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 19:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/14/its-weekend/</guid>
      <description>To learn more about where the joke came from, click this link. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First baseball game ever at Yankees Stadium, Bronx - Yankees vs. Orioles</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/03/first-baseball-game-ever-at-yankees-stadium-bronx-yankees-vs-orioles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 14:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/10/03/first-baseball-game-ever-at-yankees-stadium-bronx-yankees-vs-orioles/</guid>
      <description>First baseball game ever! Pictures from the Yankees Stadium, Bronx - Yankees vs. Orioles. Unfortunately Orioles lost that game on Saturday. They won the game on Sunday 5-2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learnt from camping in the midst of a flood</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/08/08/camping-in-the-midst-of-a-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 13:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/08/08/camping-in-the-midst-of-a-flood/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend when Ellicott City was hit with the worst storm in over hundred years, we ended up camping out in Rocky Gap State Park. Last year when we were out camping it rained a little and I had no tarp below my tent. So as soon as I got home last season, I ordered a tarp and had it ready this time. But some lessons are learned the hard way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Horrific floods in Ellicott City - Maryland and walk-up walk-down basement drain problem</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/08/07/horrific-floods-and-walk-up-walk-down-basement-drain-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 21:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/08/07/horrific-floods-and-walk-up-walk-down-basement-drain-problem/</guid>
      <description>This past week, Ellicott City, Maryland had one of the worst floods in a long time. You can see some of the devastation that it has caused in this link. Fortunately, only my basement had a little bit of flooding. But interestingly, this has been the second flooding in over a month. This made me question the drain at the bottom of the walk-down/walk-up basement.&#xA;Here is a picture of the drain at the bottom of the stairwell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bizarre fourth state of water discovered</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/18/bizarre-fourth-state-of-water-discovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 17:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/18/bizarre-fourth-state-of-water-discovered/</guid>
      <description>Bizarre fourth state of water discovered Scientists at the Oak Ridge National Lab (ORNL) have discovered that when (water) put under extreme pressure in small spaces, the life-giving liquid can exhibit a strange fourth state known as &#34;tunneling&#34;. Quantum tunneling means that a particle, or in this case a molecule, can overcome a barrier and be on both sides of it at once – or anywhere in between. Think of rolling a ball down one side of a hill and up another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article: The spherical genius of the Hüttlin Kugelmotor</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/18/article-the-spherical-genius-of-the-huttlin-kugelmotor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 17:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/18/article-the-spherical-genius-of-the-huttlin-kugelmotor/</guid>
      <description>The spherical genius of the Hüttlin Kugelmotor Electrical motors are an energy-efficient method for driving vehicles but battery technology is simply not going to advance quickly enough for all-electric vehicles to be a practical reality for most uses anytime soon. The near and mid-term future is undoubtedly a combination of compact combustion engine generators charging dense battery packs that drive electric motors - the &#34;range extender&#34; option. After nearly twenty years of development another &amp;ldquo;range extender&amp;rdquo; candidate is going through final testing and it is a work of elegant genius - Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists believe they have found a way to make a universal cancer vaccine</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/01/scientists-believe-they-have-found-a-way-to-make-a-universal-cancer-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 18:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/06/01/scientists-believe-they-have-found-a-way-to-make-a-universal-cancer-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/science/cancer-vaccine-immunotherapy-universal-immune-system-rna-nature-journal-a7060181.html</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egyptian History as we know today</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/24/egyptian-history-as-we-know-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 16:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/24/egyptian-history-as-we-know-today/</guid>
      <description>Much of the Egyptian/Nubian history and culture we know today was a result of colonization by the European empires. In their thirst for expansion, they colonized much of the known world.&#xA;In India, the Dutch, the Portuguese then the British all came under the name of colonization and expansion. They came in search of new trade-routes to the orient and as history has it, the interests of trade slowly turned into colonization and expansion of the empire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My daughter found a four-leaf clover the day before Saint Patrick&#39;s Day</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/16/my-daughter-found-a-four-leaf-clover-the-day-before-saint-patricks-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 23:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/16/my-daughter-found-a-four-leaf-clover-the-day-before-saint-patricks-day/</guid>
      <description>My daughter found a four-leaf clover the day before Saint Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day! Talk about luck!&#xA;four-leaf clover&#xA;According to the Wikipedia article:&#xA;It has been estimated that there are approximately 10,000 three-leaf clovers for every one four-leaf clover She should have played the lottery!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing vim editor for dark backgrounds so comments are not dark blue</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/15/fixing-vim-editor-for-dark-backgrounds-so-comments-are-not-dark-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 14:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2016/03/15/fixing-vim-editor-for-dark-backgrounds-so-comments-are-not-dark-blue/</guid>
      <description>Here is a simple command that can fix your vim editor for dark backgrounds so that your comments are not showing up in dark blue (unreadable).&#xA;Example screenshot:&#xA;The temporary fix is to run the following command in the vim editor:&#xA;:set background=dark instead of&#xA;:set background=light The permanent fix for this is to add the command inside $HOME/.vimrc file&#xA;set background=dark Please note that when you&amp;rsquo;re adding the property into the .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wishing everyone a Happy New Year</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/12/31/wishing-everyone-a-happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 17:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/12/31/wishing-everyone-a-happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>Wishing everyone a Happy New Year. Please feel free to copy the banner and use it on your site or share with others!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Age Of Light: Two BIG innovations in Graphene and nano technology can forge a new future for mankind</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/08/27/welcome-to-the-age-of-light-two-big-innovations-in-graphene-and-nano-technology-can-forge-a-new-future-for-mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 17:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/08/27/welcome-to-the-age-of-light-two-big-innovations-in-graphene-and-nano-technology-can-forge-a-new-future-for-mankind/</guid>
      <description>#AgeOfLight&#xA;As I was reading today&amp;rsquo;s news (Science) breakthroughs, I came across two independent discovery/invention but combined makes a HUGE breakthrough and paves the way for a BIGHTER FUTURE!!!&#xA;If this peeks your interest read further.&#xA;[#1] Invention: Manufacturing Graphene using Tea-Extract&#xA;What problem does this solve? Today, manufacturing Graphene takes a lot of time and can only produce/grow small amounts of the material. It takes a lot of energy, raw-material and time - to produce the small quantities of the product.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiking @ Centennial Park, Ellicott City, Maryland</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/08/04/hiking-centennial-park-ellicott-city-maryland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 19:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/08/04/hiking-centennial-park-ellicott-city-maryland/</guid>
      <description>Here are some great pictures I took from the hiking at the nearby Centennial Park in Ellicott City, Maryland&#xA;Click here for the complete link to the post</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interesting pics from our trip to India</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/07/09/interesting-pics-from-our-trip-to-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 15:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/07/09/interesting-pics-from-our-trip-to-india/</guid>
      <description>Interesting pics from our trip to India&#xA;I took this shot from a higher elevation against the backdrop of the Gopura (vimana) of our ancestral family temple in Kaniyur, Tamil Nadu, India. Google photo animation stitched the pictures to create the animation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valley of Lugern, Switzerland - great place to wake up each and every morning!</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/07/09/valley-of-lugern-switzerland-great-place-to-wake-up-each-and-every-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 15:36:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2015/07/09/valley-of-lugern-switzerland-great-place-to-wake-up-each-and-every-morning/</guid>
      <description>Valley of Lugern, Switzerland - great place to wake up each and every morning!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pictures from the Royal Palace Museum in Piazza San Marco, Venice, Italy</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2014/08/27/pictures-from-the-royal-palace-museum-in-piazza-san-marco-venice-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 02:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2014/08/27/pictures-from-the-royal-palace-museum-in-piazza-san-marco-venice-italy/</guid>
      <description>Here are some pictures I took from the Royal Palace Museum in Piazza San Marco, Venice, Italy [map] Shows you some of the wonderful Christian relics and how the royal family in Venice, Italy was involved in exploration of the new world, seafaring and art.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photos from Venice, Italy</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2014/08/21/photos-from-venice-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 22:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2014/08/21/photos-from-venice-italy/</guid>
      <description>Here are a few photos I took while in Venice, Italy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the new home... MyThinkPond.com</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2012/10/31/welcome-to-the-new-home-mythinkpond-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 13:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2012/10/31/welcome-to-the-new-home-mythinkpond-com/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new home of MyThinkPond.wordpress.com&#xA;www.MyThinkPond.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress Export Import Site Escaped Character Challenges - &#34; </title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2012/10/30/wordpress-export-import-site-escaped-character-chellenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 18:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2012/10/30/wordpress-export-import-site-escaped-character-chellenges/</guid>
      <description>When you export a Wordpress site and import the site into a new Wordpress site you will notice that a few HTML entities that are not allowed in an XML output got escaped. In simple terms, you will see a lot of &amp;quot; and if you use a Mac OSx system, your will see - “ and ” displayed as content in your blog pages.&#xA;Well here&amp;rsquo;s a way to correct them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Ingenious Idea : Whitelines &#43; iPhone = Great Wireframing/Design Tool</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2012/10/25/ingenious-idea-whitelines-iphone-great-wireframingdesign-tool-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 20:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2012/10/25/ingenious-idea-whitelines-iphone-great-wireframingdesign-tool-2/</guid>
      <description>I’m an Android user and today I’m wishing I owned a iPhone or iPad after seeing this idea…&#xA;It’s called Whitelines.&#xA;To create a printable paper that uses “white-lines” instead of the usual “solid-black/blue lines” and to take it a step further to add some scan marks such that a iPhone can take a digital picture of your notes and make it available online. The possibilities are endless.&#xA;Here how the process works:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desktop timer for Pomodoro Technique users</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2011/07/14/desktop-timer-for-pomodoro-technique-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 12:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2011/07/14/desktop-timer-for-pomodoro-technique-users/</guid>
      <description>If you are looking to improve your productivity when you are working on a mindful task then Pomodoro Technique is the way.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s a technique where you sit for twenty-five minutes at a time focused on one task. At the end of the cycle, you take a &amp;ldquo;required&amp;rdquo; short break and then start on your next cycle.&#xA;Why twenty-five minutes and not thirty? If you find out why, let me know.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tired of &#34;Terminate batch job (Y/N)?&#34;, try this</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2011/06/25/tired-of-terminate-batch-job-yn-try-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 03:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2011/06/25/tired-of-terminate-batch-job-yn-try-this/</guid>
      <description>When you invoke a batch file or most applications in a command-prompt and when you wish to close the application by doing a CTRL+C, you get the annoying &amp;ldquo;Terminate batch job (Y/N)?&amp;rdquo; prompt. And in most cases, even if you type a &amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo;, it still kills the application. Example is the Tomcat startup. To avoid this, try this:&#xA;[sourcecode language=&amp;ldquo;jscript&amp;rdquo;]&#xA;YourScript.cmd &amp;lt; Nul&#xA;[/sourcecode]&#xA;This should no longer ask you with the annoying prompt &amp;ldquo;Terminate batch job (Y/N)?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>questions and thoughts about twitter</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2010/07/29/questions-and-thoughts-about-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 20:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2010/07/29/questions-and-thoughts-about-twitter/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Twitter for sometime now. And I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered about the settings in Twitter, especially one particular setting - &amp;ldquo;public vs private&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Let me first review the setting. If you set your privacy settings to &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo;, then all posts after that time-line will only be available to the followers that you have allowed. And if at some point of time, you decide to toggle it to &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo;, then all posts (even the ones you sent in the past - as private) becomes open to the public.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humor of the day on Fourier Transform</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2010/02/24/humor-of-the-day-on-fourier-transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 22:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2010/02/24/humor-of-the-day-on-fourier-transform/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s an IEEE joke. This one got me laughing for quite some time. http://xkcd.com/26/ http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/fourier.jpg&#xA;Cheers</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neat little tool for your browser toolkit - GrabNZip.com</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2009/11/25/neat-little-tool-for-your-browser-toolkit-grabnzip-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 16:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2009/11/25/neat-little-tool-for-your-browser-toolkit-grabnzip-com/</guid>
      <description>Found a neat little browser download helper tool. It&amp;rsquo;s one that I&amp;rsquo;ll be using and it&amp;rsquo;s definitely a tool to add to your browser toolkit bookmarks.&#xA;Ever been in a situation where you wanted to download a file at the office but the particular extension is not allowed at the company. Well, this tool might help you in those situations. It&amp;rsquo;s called Grab-N-Zip (http://www.GrabNZip.com)&#xA;You enter your URL to the file that you are trying to &amp;ldquo;grab&amp;rdquo; from the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opening a link in a PDF document in a new window</title>
      <link>http://MyThinkPond.com/2009/11/04/opening-a-link-in-a-pdf-document-in-a-new-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 16:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://MyThinkPond.com/2009/11/04/opening-a-link-in-a-pdf-document-in-a-new-window/</guid>
      <description>Open Link In PDF In New Window&#xA;Sometimes you like to link out to other URL&amp;rsquo;s or other PDF&amp;rsquo;s from within a PDF document. And you will notice that this replaces the existing HTML frame (if you had served the original PDF from a website) or window with the new document making it hard to navigate. In these cases, you would prefer to open the link in the PDF onto it&amp;rsquo;s own new window.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
